free-vpn-proxy.com 2012-12-04

# AnchorFree Hotspot Shield Privacy & Security Policy - Get behind the Shield

## Protecting the web for your security, privacy and anonymity!   
Get behind the SHIELD!

#### Last Modified: December 13, 2011

Welcome, and thank you for your interest in AnchorFree, Inc, AnchorFree GmbH and or Affiliates ("AnchorFree"), and its Hotspot Shield software ("Hotspot Shield"). This Privacy Notice describes what information is collected by us from any user of the Hotspot Shield Free Version (collectively or individually "User(s)"), as well as our use and disclosure of that information.

**NOTE TO KIDS:** HOTSPOT SHIELD IS NOT AVAILABLE TO PERSONS UNDER THE AGE OF 18. 

_If you are under 18 years of age, please do not use Hotspot Shield._

#### Our Commitment to User Privacy:1

AnchorFree does not collect any personally identifiable information on Hotspot Shield. Hotspot Shield automatically collects certain non-personally identifiable information from Users that is used in the aggregate only. AnchorFree does not collect, store, or share any permanent identifiers of Users, including IP addresses. Please note that Hotspot Shield only enables privacy and encrypts user Internet sessions when it is turned ON. Having Hotspot Shield on the desktop, without turning it ON does not do anything. Unless Users turn Hotspot Shield ON and opt into the service, Hotspot Shield will be completely idle.

#### Our Commitment to Web Security:

Hotspot Shield encrypts every page visited by our Users, thus protecting communications between each User and the Internet. AnchorFree Hotspot Shield employs certain physical, managerial, and technical safeguards to preserve the integrity and security of any information collected. We cannot, however, ensure or warrant that the safeguards will be uninterrupted or effective, or that any information you transmit to AnchorFree Hotspot Shield will remain secure, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission of information, AnchorFree employs certain techniques and technologies to ensure the security of our systems. However, please note that this is not a guarantee that such information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards. If AnchorFree learns of a security systems breach, we may post a notice on the AnchorFree website to notify Users. Please note that Hotspot Shield helps secure your Internet session, not your computer. Hotspot Shield does not protect your computer from viruses or malware. We recommend getting anti-virus/anti-malware solutions from one of our reputable partners in order to also help secure your computer.

#### The Information Hotspot Shield Collects:

**"Cookies" Information.** When you use Hotspot Shield, we may send one or more cookies - a small text file containing a string of alphanumeric characters - to your computer. Hotspot Shield uses both session cookies and persistent cookies. A persistent cookie remains after you close your browser and may be used by your browser on subsequent use of Hotspot Shield. These persistent types of cookies can be removed, but each web browser is a little different, so please look through your browser "Help" file to learn the correct way to modify your cookies set-up.

**"Automatically Collected" Information.** When you use the Hotspot Shield, we automatically record certain information from your web browser by using different types of proprietary technology, including cookies. The automatically-collected information does not identify a User personally, and AnchorFree only uses the automatically collected information in the aggregate for various purposes, including but not limited to monitoring the advertisements displayed on the Hotspot Shield.

#### The Way AnchorFree Uses Information Collected from Hotspot Shield:

AnchorFree may use automatically-collected information in the aggregate to monitor the advertisements displayed on the Hotspot Shield, and for purposes of research or analysis. Please note that by having Hotspot Shield on your computer, but not turned on, no information is collected by AnchorFree. Anonymous web information may only be collected when you turn Hotspot Shield ON.

#### When AnchorFree Discloses Information Collected from Hotspot Shield:

AnchorFree may share anonymous data with a variety of third parties, including its affiliates, advertisers, and other current and prospective business partners. AnchorFree may use anonymous data collected for website administration, advertising, and promotional purposes, and may share such information with various affiliated and unaffiliated entities for such purposes.  
AnchorFree may also enter into agreements with outside companies that possess technology that allows us to customize the advertising and marketing messages Users receive while using the Hotspot Shield, and those outside companies may have access to anonymous data that we collect from Hotspot Shield users.  
AnchorFree may disclose automatically collected and other aggregate non-personally-identifiable information with interested third parties to assist such parties in understanding the usage, viewing, and demographic patterns for certain programs, content, services, advertisements, promotions, and/or functionality on the Hotspot Shield. 

#### Third-party Advertisers, Links to Other Sites on the Hotspot Shield:

AnchorFree allows other companies, called third-party ad servers or ad networks, to serve advertisements within Hotspot Shield. These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to send, directly to your browser, the advertisements and links that appear on the Hotspot Shield. Any third parties including advertisers may automatically receive the virtual IP Address assigned by AnchorFree. Your original IP address will not be collected or provided to any third parties by AnchorFree. Advertisers may also use other technologies (such as cookies, javascript, or web beacons) to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and to personalize their advertising content. AnchorFree's Hotspot Shield Privacy Notice does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or other web sites visited by Users. Please note that this Privacy Notice will not apply to your activities or any information you disclose while using any third-party products or services or otherwise interacting with third parties. How third parties handle and use your personal information related to their sites and services is governed by their security, privacy and other policies, if any, and not this Privacy Notice. AnchorFree has no responsibility for any third party's policies, or any third party's compliance with them. Anyone may opt out of the cookies as directed by NAI opt-out page, which is currently located at <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>

#### Changes and Updates to this Hotspot Shield Privacy Notice:

This Hotspot Shield Privacy Notice may be revised periodically and this will be reflected by the "last modified" notice above. Please revisit this page to stay aware of any changes. Your continued use of the Hotspot Shield constitutes your agreement to this Hotspot Shield Privacy Notice and any future revisions.

#### AnchorFree Contact Information:

Please contact AnchorFree with any questions or comments about this Hotspot Shield Privacy Notice at info@anchorfree.com. Please note that if you contact AnchorFree, you will be disclosing your personal information, and the use of such personal information will be governed by the AnchorFree Privacy Policy.
